polkatheatre.com 2019-01-20

# Privacy Policy - Polka Theatre

**Polka Respects Your Privacy**

**240 The Broadway, Wimbledon, London, SW19 1SB**

Polka Children’s Theatre Ltd (Polka) is a registered charity no. 256979. We are committed to protecting your privacy and will only use your personal information in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (DPA), Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (PECR), General Data Protection Regulation 25 May 2018 (GDPR) and other relevant legislation.

**Our Privacy Policy is set out below: please read it with care as it describes how we will process your data and that of your children.**

**Data Security and Storage**

We collect and store personal and non-personal data that you may volunteer as part of booking tickets, making a purchase, becoming a Member or via donation forms, e-news sign-ups, visitor surveys or in connection with a specific project or event.

**Personal information we collect may include:** ** **

  * Your full name and title and date of birth
  * Postal address, email address and phone number
  * IP (internet protocol) address
  * Ticket purchase history
  * Gift Aid status
  * Payment card details (these are not stored, except if you have requested an Automatic Renewal Membership when they are stored securely by Sage Pay, an approved third party)
  * Your contact and communication preferences – _the information you have opted to receive from Polka about our programmes and how you want to receive this_

**Non-personal information** we collect includes: IP addresses (the location of the computer on the internet); web pages accessed; and files downloaded. This helps us to determine how many people use our website, how regularly they visit, and how popular our webpages are. This information does not tell us anything about who you are or where you live, but it does help us monitor and improve our service.

We store personal data under strict safekeeping and confidentiality measures on secure servers operated by Polka and stored securely by Spektrix, our ticketing, marketing and fundraising systems provider. All Spektrix servers are located in a Tier IV data centre in the UK, which has 24/7 onsite security and tightly restricted access control. Only authorised Polka staff who need to process your data will have access to it.

By disclosing your personal information to us via [polkatheatre.com](http://glyndebourne.com/), by phone or in writing, you are giving us your consent to collect, store and process your personal information in the manner described in this Notice. The information we hold will be accurate and up-to-date within our knowledge.

While we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur when it is under our control, we use our best efforts to try to prevent this. Unfortunately, the transmission of data across the internet is not completely secure and while we do our best to try to protect the security of your information we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur while data is being transferred.

If you have any questions regarding the Privacy Notice or your information, please email: [dataprotection@polkatheatre.com](mailto:dataprotection@polkatheatre.com) or write to Data Protection, Polka Theatre, 240 The Broadway, London SW19 1SB.

**We will use the information you provide to:**

  * Process sales transactions, donations or other payments and verify financial transactions
  * Fulfil your requests – such as applications for membership, donations, competition entries, participation in campaigns and provision of information
  * Identify visitors and contributors
  * Handle and deliver orders and communicate with you about them
  * Provide a personalised service to you when you visit our website. This could include customising the content and/or layout of our pages for individual users
  * Record any contact we have with you
  * Prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our website and enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf in relation to prevention and detection
  * Carry out research on the demographics, interests and behaviour of our users and supporters to help Polka gain a better understanding of them and to enable us to improve our service. This research is usually carried out internally by our employees unless we notify you otherwise and have your prior consent.
  * Communicate with our customers and supporters

**And only with your consent** , provide you with information that we think may be of interest to you, including the ‘Remember when?’ Polka Memories campaign and opportunities to support Polka projects, such as our FUTURE POLKA theatre redevelopment

**Sharing information**

To undertake our business activities we sometimes have to share your information with third parties such as our database and IT providers and our mailing house, which handles our direct postal communications with you. We only choose partners we trust and will only pass personal data to them if they have signed a contract that requires them to:

  * abide by the requirements of the Data Protection Act
  * treat your information as carefully as we would
  * only use the information for the purposes it was supplied (and not for their own purposes or the purposes of any other organisation)
  * allow us to carry out checks to ensure they are doing all these things.

Polka is a National Portfolio Organisation (NPO) and as such receives public funding from Arts Council England. We are therefore required to collaborate with and share personal customer data with other NPOs. This information is only used by publicly-funded arts organisations in England to better understand their audiences and improve their cultural offer. You will be given the option to share your personal data with our relevant NPO partners.

We _do not_ share or sell your personal information for other organisations to use for their own purposes, unless it is for the reasons given above.

**Fundraising support for Polka’s work and FUTURE POLKA redevelopment**

As a charity, Polka fundraises from individuals, companies, public bodies and private trusts and foundations. This includes approaching those who want to support our mission to inspire as many children possible aged 0-12 years and from all backgrounds by enabling them to experience thrilling, innovative, world-class theatre and creative learning opportunities in a welcoming space that they can call their own. Fundraising also helps to ensure the financial viability of Polka as we strive to achieve our long-held desire to redevelop and improve our premises for future generations.

When fundraising, we may undertake research to explore shared interests with potential supporters. We will not use third-party profiling companies but may use profiling and screening techniques ourselves to analyse your personal data and create a profile of your interests and preferences. We may also make use of additional information about you including where you live, your age and similar demographics, and any publicly-available information (for example through LinkedIn, Companies House, Charity Commission).

We want to contact you only when it may be relevant. By better understanding the background of our supporters we are able to make only the most appropriate requests for gifts that will help us continue to make pioneering, world-class theatre and learning programmes for children created by the most talented artists, develop talent and make live theatre accessible to children with wide ranging additional needs and from all backgrounds.

**Children and Vulnerable Adults**

We are committed to safeguarding children, young people and vulnerable adults and do all we can to ensure that all who work at Polka, including volunteers, whether on stage or joining an education project, are safe and inspired by their experience. An important part of doing this is to protect their privacy.

If you are aged 16 or under, please obtain your parent / guardian’s permission every time before you provide any personal information; we will always require their signature on any documentation when you sign up to a Polka project or are contracted to perform with us. We will always require the carer’s signature on similar documentation relating to vulnerable adults.

**You choose what information you get from Polka and how you get it**

You can opt-in to receive communication about some or all aspects of Polka and our work for and with children AND how you wish to communicate with Polka for each or all of these, including by email, post, telephone or text.

**Update your permission preferences or stop Polka communication at any time**

You can easily update your personal information and communications preferences, or unsubscribe, at any time in the following ways:

  * online by logging into [My Account](https://polkatheatre.com/my-account)
  * clicking on the ‘unsubscribe’ link within a newsletter or within an email
  * by emailing us at [dataprotection@polkatheatre.com](mailto:dataprotection@polkatheatre.com)
  * by writing to Data Protection, Polka Theatre, 240 The Broadway, London SW19 1SB

The permissions above relate to optional communications from Polka. We will continue to send you communications about transactions you make with us, for example when you purchase tickets, or relating to active subscriptions you hold with us such as a membership, or if there is a query regarding your purchase from our shop. Each email we send will give you the option to update your preferences. We will consider that your preferences last for _five years_ unless you notify us otherwise.

**Polka Family and Friends and Production Supporters’ subscriptions**

If you hold an active membership this will include sending you information regarding your subscription renewal, two season brochures per year, your Membership e-news about priority booking, and your Automatic Renewal confirmation (if you have selected this option).

**External links**

Our website contains links to other sites whose information practice may be different to ours. You should consult other sites’ privacy notices as we have no control over information that is submitted to or collected by third parties. Furthermore we cannot guarantee the privacy of personal information you transmit over the web or that may be collectable in transit by others.

**Access to and deletion of your personal data held by Polka**

You have the right to ask for a free copy of the personal information that we hold about you (to be supplied within one month of receiving request) to correct any inaccuracies in that information (to be corrected within 72 hours of receiving request) or to ask us to delete such records. Please direct all requests to [ dataprotection@polkatheatre.com](mailto:dataprotection@polkatheatre.com) or write to Data Protection, Polka Theatre, 240 The Broadway, London SW19 1SB.

You have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office if we have not been able to satisfactorily resolve a problem about our handling of your personal information. For more information about your Data Protection rights, please visit the website of the Information Commissioner’s Office at ico.org.uk

_Updated: 23 November 2017_
